[GRISHA TITAN grunting]
Why is there still so much
you refuse to show me?
I never saw
the fall of the walls.
What becomes of my home?
Is Carla going to make it?
Was there no other way forward?
Was this really
the right choice?
[GRISHA] You're here
watching me now, right, Zeke?
[GRISHA]
From here on out,
nothing is going to go
the way you'd hoped.
Eren will get
everything he wants.
What do you mean?
How could you know--?
[GRISHA]
I've seen it.
I've witnessed Eren's memories.
What humanity is about to endure
is far worse than
I could imagine.
[GRISHA gasps]
Zeke.
That's you, right, Zeke?
You've gotten so big!
I'm sorry.
I know I was never
the father you deserved.
After all I put you through,
you have every right
to despise me.
[Sobs] But even so.
I will always love you.
If only I'd let you be my son
instead of trying to
make you a soldier!
[GRISHA sobbing]
Oh, Father.
Please, Zeke.
You have to stop Eren.
[ZEKE gasps]
[Groans]
[Gasps]
It's a shame we couldn't
stick around long enough
to watch me eat him.
It was all you?
Father followed through,
attacked the king of the walls,
and challenged
the world because
you pushed him to?
If what he said
back then is true...
If you can transcend time
with the Attack Titan's power,
then he only would have
seen whatever memories
you chose to show him.
You could manipulate him
into changing the past!
Our father, Grisha,
was on the verge of
completing the
Restorationists' mission.
And then he got cold feet.
He was scared of
losing his family.
Realizing even if he took
the Founder, he couldn't use it.
But he did,
despite knowing that,
and he entrusted it to you.
Because he'd witnessed memories
from further into the future.
Things that're
still yet to come.
Things you showed him.
With a little help from you.
If you hadn't dragged me
into his memories,
I could never have
pulled it off.
Thank you for that, Brother.
[Gasps] He said things
wouldn't go my way.
That you'd get
everything you wanted.
So. Does that mean--?
Yeah. It happened
around four years ago.
Dad's visions of my own future
memories were revealed to me.
What a sight to see.
Founder Ymir!
Take the ability to reproduce
from every last
one of your subjects!
[EREN gasps]
The Coordinate!
[ZEKE]
You know what Grisha said to me?
"Zeke, you have to
stop Eren. Please."
Seems you left him saddled
with a great deal of regret.
[ZEKE] I can't know
what all you've seen.
How much of your
future you witnessed
in Father's memories.
But you can't have found out
everything that's
in store for you.
After all, you came here
without realizing
that you wouldn't be able
to control the Founder.
[ZEKE] Even now.
You're as powerless as ever.
[EREN yelling]
[Gasps] There's no point. Eren.
Ymir has accepted her orders
and begun moving.
[ZEKE] Nothing in this world
can stop her now.
♪ Opening Song ♪
[FRIEDA]
That's amazing, Historia!
Just look at how well
you're able to read now!
Thank you, but it's only 'cause
you're here to teach me.
[FRIEDA] Ah.That runny nose of
yours needs some tending to.
I guess next, I should teach you
how to act more ladylike.
Here. Blow into this.
Ooh! Goodness.
That's a job well done.
--[HISTORIA] Hey.
--[FRIEDA] Hm?
What's it mean to act ladylike?
Uh-- Well. Let me think.
I'm not exactly
an expert myself, but...
I would say that the young lady
here in your book has it down.
So. Is she one of
your favorite characters?
[HISTORIA]
Mm-hm!
[FRIEDA] She's always
thinking about others,
and helping them out
in whatever way she can.
[FRIEDA]
You'll find pain and suffering
everywhere you look
in this world.
[FRIEDA] So do your best
to make things better.
[FRIEDA] Treat people with love
and they'll love you in return.
[FRITZ]
A pig escaped.
One of you allowed
that to happen.
If they won't confess,
then I'll pluck an eye
from each of your skulls
and call this settled.
Slaves can easily go about
their work with one apiece.
So you allowed my pig to escape?
Then so be it.
I hereby set you free.
[FOUNDER YMIR panting]
[FOUNDER YMIR yelps]
[Gasps]
[Horse neighs]
[Roars]
[FRITZ]
My slave, Ymir.
You have done such
great works in my name.
You have carved out roads,
cultivated the hinterlands,
and built bridges
spanning mountains.
You have helped
the tribe of Eldia
to become both
large and powerful.
For all this, I shall
reward you with my seed.
[FRITZ] The Marleyans
are our hated foes.
In the name of Fritz,
bring them death!
[Inaudible]
What is the meaning of this?
On your feet.
My slave could never be
done in by a single spear.
Of that I am certain.
Now rise and do your work, Ymir.
Do it. Feast, my daughters!
We must bear Ymir's power
into the future,
no matter the cost.
Consume every scrap and
sinew of your mother's body.
Maria. Rose. Sina.
[FRITZ]
My daughters.
You must give birth
and multiply.
The blood of Ymir
has to live on.
When you yourselves die,
let my grandchildren
eat your spines.
And let their children
eat their spines.
So forth and so on. Forever!
[FRITZ] Even after my passing,
my Eldians shall
wield Ymir's power and reign
supreme all over the world.
Our Titans will bring the people
of every land to heel.
So long as this world persists,
our reign will--
[EREN]
I'll end it! Here and now!
I'll put an end to this world
if you give me your strength!
You're nobody's slave
and you're no god, either!
You're just a person!
You don't have to serve anyone.
You can make your own choices!
This is your power.
You get to decide!
Do you wanna stay here...
Wait, Eren. Stop it!
You can't do this!
What the hell are you thinking?
Ymir! I gave you a command.
You have to obey my will!
You've been guiding me
this whole time, haven't you?
[ZEKE] What are you waiting for?
Do it, Ymir!
You've been all alone, waiting.
[ZEKE] I'm descended from
Eldian royalty. Obey me!
[EREN] Two thousand years,
for someone.
[ALL gasp]
[MAGATH screams]
[Screams]
[Gasps]
[EREN TITAN roars]
[REINER]
Gabi!
[MIKASA]
What is that thing?
It's gigantic.
It looked like it materialized
from where Eren was.
Could it be...
Eren really did it. It's over!
I can't hear you!
The war is over and we won!
Huh?
Eren's using the power
of the Founder!
[MIKASA gasps]
That has to be why
the rumbling has started.
This is what Eren
wanted all along.
He's gonna send
these Titans to Marley
and crush the global
military alliance!
Eren's still our ally!
He always has been!
Zeke, did you...?
Eren. Are you still yourself?
Have you really
come back to our side?
Wait a second. What's going on?
There's no way. He would never.
Mikasa!
[Gasps]
[ARMIN] All the walls are
falling, even Wall Maria!
But he doesn't need that many
Titans to attack Marley.
This is complete overkill!
Just the wall around Shiganshina
would be more than enough.
He has no reason to give up
the walls completely.
Not if the plan is
just to knock out
the global alliance in Marley.
So why do this?
What could he be--?
[EREN]
Hear me. Subjects of Ymir.
[MIKASA gasps] It's him.
That was Eren's voice!
[EREN]
My name is Eren Jaeger.
I'm addressing my fellow
Subjects of Ymir.
Speaking to you directly through
the power of the Founder.
All the walls
on the island of Paradis
have crumbled to the ground,
and the legions of Titans buried
within have begun their march.
[EREN]
My only goal
is to protect the lives of
the people of Paradis,
the island where I was born.
[EREN] Right now, the nations
of the world are united
in their desire to
exterminate my people,
and it won't end
with our island.
They won't be satisfied until
every last Subject
of Ymir is dead.
I won't let them have their way.
The Titans of the walls
will continue their march
until every trace of life beyond
our shores is trampled flat,
and the people of Paradis are
all that remains of humanity.
♪ Ending Song ♪
[NARRATOR]
The ground rumbles underfoot.
A pillar of dust
touches the sky,
heralding the horde of
Titans on the horizon.
The walls of Paradis are gone.
Next episode: "Thaw."